Guide to the Arthur Willert Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1910-1957; Series I; 2' (6 boxes)
  - General Correspondence
    - Rousseau, Theodore
      See: box 1, folder 4
    - Royal Institute of International Affairs, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 161)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/1
    - Royden, T., 1919 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Sargint, ____, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Scott, Walter S., 1915, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Sedgwick, Ellery
      See: box 1, folder 9
    - Seymour, Charles, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Shaw, ____, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 166)
      See also: box 16, folder 118
    - Shipley, A. G., 1918 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Shove, G. T., 1938 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Simon, John, 1933, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Simonds, Frank H., 1919 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Smith, C. Howard, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Sparks, H. C., 1915 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Spender, J. A., 1927 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Spens, Will, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Spring-Rice, Cecil A., 1912-1914, undated (Box 4, Folder 175)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 10/0
    - Spring-Rice, Thomas, undated (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Steed, Wickham, 1914 February-April (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Steed, Wickham, 1914 May-December (Box 5, Folder 178)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 6/12
    - Steed, Wickham, 1915 January-August (Box 5, Folder 179)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/7
    - Steed, Wickham, 1915 September-December (Box 5, Folder 180)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 3/7
    - Steed, Wickham, 1916-1918 (Box 5, Folder 181)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 4/5
    - Steed, Wickham, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Stuart, Campbell, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Sullivan, Mark, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Taft, Hulbert, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Talbot-Ponsonby, Arthur H. B., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Tardieu, André, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - The Times, 1911, 1914-1919, undated (Box 5, Folder 188)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 13/6
    - Thwaites, Norman, 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Tree, Herbert N., 1917 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Trohan, Walter, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Tweedie, Alec, n.y. (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - Tweedie, Mrs. Alec, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Tyrrell, William, 1919-1922, 1924-1925, undated (Box 5, Folder 194)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 8/9
    - Vandervelde, Alla, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Vansittart, Robert G., 1922, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Vernon, Leroy T., 1912 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Verney, Harry C. W., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Walter, ____, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Walter, Hubert, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Wantage, Lady, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 201)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 0/3
    - Washington, Booker T., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Watson, ____, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Watson, [Anna?] Grant, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - Weeks, Edward
    - Wilberforce, Robert, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Wilberforce, Robert, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 206)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 0/8
    - Wiley, Louis, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 207)
    - Willert, Florence S.
      See: box 6, folder 216-239
    - Willert, P. F., 1911, undated (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - Willert, Mrs. P. F., undated (Box 5, Folder 209)
    - Willison, J. S., 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - Wiseman, William, 1917, undated (Box 5, Folder 211)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 2/6
    - Wiseman, William, 1918, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 212)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 5/6
    - Wrench, Evelyn, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Incomplete and illegible signatures, 1910-1911, 1913-1918, 1920, 1928, undated (Box 5, Folder 214)
      Letters To AW / From AW: 12/2
    - Microfiche of correspondence from the Archives of The Times, London, 1905-1921 (Box 5, Folder 215)
      See: Microfiche No. 52
    - See also:
      box 14, folders 57-58
      box 14, folder 62
  - Florence S. Willert Correspondence
    - Beevor, C. F., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 216)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 2/0
    - Churchill, Winston, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Grigg, Edward, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 218)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 1/0
      See also: box 3, folder 90-92
    - Hill, George, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Lander, Henry, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - McCay, Charles, undated (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Myers, Bernard, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 222)
      See also: box 3, folder 131
    - Northcliffe, Lord, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1932-1933, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 224)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 9/0
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 225)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 8/0
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 226)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 3/0
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 227)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 5/0
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1947-1949, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 228)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 10/0
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Seidmore, Eliza R., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Spring-Rice, Florence, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Willert, Arthur, 1918 December - 1919 (Box 6, Folder 232)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 11/3
    - Willert, Arthur, 1921 October-November (Box 6, Folder 233)
      To FSW/ From FSW: 12/0
    - Willert, Arthur, 1921 December 2-14 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - Willert, Arthur, 1921 December 17-30 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Willert, Arthur, 1922 January 2-20 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    - Willert, Arthur, 1922 January 22 - February 10 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    - Willert, Arthur, 1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 238)
    - Illegible signatures (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Northcliffe Mission Correspondence
    - 1917 July - August 15 (Box 6, Folder 240)
    - 1917 August 16 - December (Box 6, Folder 241)
- Writings, (1907-1920) - (1935-1939) - 1964; Series II; 8' 2" (21 boxes)
  Articles for The Times (6 boxes): This section contains the clippings and some drafts of the articles Willert wrote from 1907 until 1920 when he served as Washington correspondent for The Times of London. The material is arranged chronologically.
  Memoranda, notes and Press Releases (2 boxes): This section contains memoranda, some of which were originally marked "Confidential," written by Willert on a variety of subjects, Willert's notes from meetings and interviews, and the press releases he wrote in his capacity as Press Officer of the Foreign Office from 1920 to 1935. The material spans Willert's activities from World War I through the end of World War II and is arranged chronologically.
  North American Newspaper Alliance Articles (1 box): This sections consists of the clippings and drafts of Willert's articles on political conditions in Britain, Italy, and Germany from 1936 to 1939. The articles are arranged chronologically.
  Magazine Articles (1 1/2 boxes): This section contains typescripts and reprints of magazine articles written by Willert. The material is arranged chronologically.
  Lectures (1/2 box): This section consists of Willert's resumé, the itineraries from his lecture tours through the United States in 1936 and 1939, the syllabus of a lecture course, and a few of his lectures on miscellaneous topics.
  Books and Reviews (5 boxes): This section contains reviews of seven books written by Willert. There are also the typed manuscripts, typed and handwritten drafts, and rewritten chapters from two of his books: From Thames to Potomac and Washington and Other Memories (originally titled Decline Through Victory ). Finally, there is a large quantity of handwritten drafts for an unidentified book, which are arranged by chapter number.
  notebooks and Appointment Books (4 boxes): This section consists of notebooks compiled by Willert on his travels and for his writing and of appointment books from various years, all of which is arranged chronologically.
  Informational File (1 box): This section consists of newspaper and magazine articles and pamphlets written by other people on a variety of subjects which were collected by Willert.
  - Articles for The Times
    - "Mostly Porter,", 1907 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1907 February - 1909 January (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
    - 1909 February-Nov, 1910 - 1912 March (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
    - 1912 March - 1913 April (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1913 April 11 - 1914 April 22 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1914 April 23 - 1915 May 6 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - [1915 May - 1916 Jun] (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 1916 June - 1918 November (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - [1918 October - 1919 Nov] (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - [1919 November - 1920 Oct] (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Why cotton was declared contraband, 1915 August (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Germany and the United States,", [1915] September 15 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Times telegram delayed and mutilated compared with Morning Post article just delayed (re: Kim decision), 1915 September 17 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Severing diplomatic relations with Germany, 1917 February 3 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - "The eighteen months that preceded the rupture of diplomatic relations with Germany on February 3, 1917…" (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "It is obvious that war for the United States must for a long time mean maritime operations…" (article complimentary to the United States navy), 1917 April (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Memoranda, notes and Press Releases
    - Memorandum: politics: Canada, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Memorandum for the Foreign Office but not transmitted by Ambassador owing to dispute with The Times for alleged abuse of French Yellow Book, 1914 November (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Confidential memorandum: The Times and the French Yellow Book, [ca. 1914 Nov] (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Propaganda: memorandum re: request of United Press Association to interview British public men and send a correspondent to the British lines, 1914 or 1915 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Memorandum for Spring-Rice, 1915 July 21 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "For Flanagan" re: cotton as contraband, 1915 August 5 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Account of conversation between Spring-Rice and Lansing, 1915 October 16 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - British propaganda proposals: Pomeroy Burton's Report, 1917 April (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - British propaganda proposals: modifications suggested for Burton's plan [by Willert], [1917?] (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Memorandum for Lord Reading before his meeting with President Wilson, 1917 September 20 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - "The War Machinery of Washington," memorandum for Lord Northcliffe and Lord Reading, 1917 November 3 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Memorandum re: the League of Nations, 1918 August (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Report to Foreign Office about the Democratic Convention, 1920 July (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - notes of conversations in France with Lord Hardinge of Penshurst, Sir Ronald Lindsay, and George Adam, 1920 December (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Memoranda re: "Lord Northcliffe's campaign in the U. S. A. against H. M. Government", 1921 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Washington Conference: Report to the Foreign Office, 1921 May (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Memoranda: Viscount Grey of Fallodon and the Magna Carta Association, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Press statement in reply to Lloyd George interview re: "secret compacts" of 1919, 1924 January (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Memoranda: Press Department Organization, 1924 December 17 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Memorandum: Northcliffe's last days (as related to Willert by Wickham Steed, Geneva), 1929 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Memorandum: promotion, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Lausanne Conference: Willert's notes; published list of delegates, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: Willert's handwritten "Disarmament Diary" (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: Willert's introductory statement to the press, undated (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: memorandum for the Prime Minister: press reception, undated (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: Willert's handwritten notes, 1932 February-April (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: [Bruny] at Geneva, 1932 April (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: memorandum for the Prime Minister: International Press Lunch, 1932 April 22 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: statement dictated by the Prime Minister, 1932 April 26 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: notes (Box 13, Folder 49)
      See also: box 5, folder 196
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: notes, 1932 November (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: miscellaneous statements for the press, 1932 November (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: memorandum: "Relations with the Secretary of State", 1932 November 27 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: notes and statements to the press, 1933 January-February (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: memoranda re: "crisis", 1933 October (Box 14, Folder 54)
      See also: box 2, folder 109
      See also: box 4, folder 152
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: notes, 1933 November (Box 14, Folder 55)
    - notes and press releases, 1933 December (Box 14, Folder 55a)
    - Memoranda and statements to the press re: current events, 1934 January (Box 14, Folder 56)
    - Geneva Disarmament Conference: notes, 1934 February (Box 14, Folder 56a)
    - Memoranda regarding Willert's disputes with the Foreign Office which led to his resignation (includes correspondence), 1934 (Box 14, Folder 57)
    - Willert's Farewell to the Foreign Office: luncheon speeches and correspondence, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 58)
    - Confidential memorandum re: visits with Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1936 April 14 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    - The Unpleasant Side, 1939 January (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Conversation with Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1939 March 25-26 (Box 14, Folder 61)
    - Memoranda and correspondence re: Willert's World War II activities (includes Bolero Committee), 1939-1945, undated (Box 14, Folder 62)
    - British propaganda: memorandum written thirty years later, 1947 June 24 (Box 14, Folder 63)
    - Memorandum: American newspapers in the war, undated (Box 14, Folder 64)
    - Confidential memorandum re: the appointment of an officer to supervise military speakers, undated (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - Interview with Colonel House?, undated (Box 14, Folder 66)
    - Memorandum: "The British Educational Mission in America,", undated (Box 14, Folder 67)
    - Miscellaneous notes and outlines, undated (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - North American Newspaper Alliance Articles
    - "What America Thinks" (two parts), 1936 April (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - 1937 August-December (Box 15, Folder 70-71)
    - "Henry Ford's Peace Ark", 1937 November 11 (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - "Democracy Needs This Treaty", 1938 February 1 (Box 15, Folder 73)
    - 1938 February-Dec, 1939 April-June (Box 15, Folder 74-77)
    - 1939 April-May (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - Miscellaneous news articles, undated (Box 15, Folder 79)
  - Magazine Articles
    - "The Last Refuge of the Spoilsman," The Atlantic Monthly, pp. 433-445., 1914 April (Box 16, Folder 80)
    - "The Problem of the Associated Press," The Atlantic Monthly, pp. 132-137., 1914 July (Box 16, Folder 81)
    - "'Tommy Atkins' in the Field," World's Work, pp. 25-27, 1914 November (Box 16, Folder 82)
    - "What England and Germany Expect of Us: Anglo-American Relations — and the War," World's Work, pp. 181-185., 1914 December (Box 16, Folder 83)
    - "England's View of Contraband," The New Republic, pp. 14-15., 1915 January 9 (Box 16, Folder 84)
    - "The Vexed Question of Contraband," The Atlantic Monthly, pp. 263-270., 1915 February (Box 16, Folder 85)
    - "The Australasian Military System," World's Work, pp. 419-421., 1915 February (Box 16, Folder 86)
    - "Why the World Is Against Germany," World's Work, pp. 134-135E (incomplete)., 1915 June (Box 16, Folder 87)
    - "England's New Cabinet of 'All the Talents,'" World's Work, pp. 321-328., 1915 July (Box 16, Folder 88)
    - "The Malady of Europe," The Round Table, pp. 751-781., 1922 September (Box 16, Folder 89)
    - "An English View of Anglo-American Relations," Foreign Affairs, pp. 59-70., 1922 December (Box 16, Folder 90)
    - Article about Franklin D. Roosevelt (not published), 1936 (Box 16, Folder 91)
    - "When the Next War Comes In Europe…," The Saturday Review, pp. 6-7., 1936 January 25 (Box 16, Folder 92)
    - "…Can America Stay Out?," review of "Can We Be Neutral?," by Allen W. Dulles and Hamilton Fish Armstrong, The Saturday Review, p.7, 1936 January 25 (Box 16, Folder 93)
    - "The Foreign Office from Within," Strand Magazine, pp. 398-405., 1936 February (Box 16, Folder 94)
    - "England and the World Crisis," and "Europe in 1936," Institute of Public Affairs, pp. 39-65., 1936 June (Box 16, Folder 95)
    - "Sir Arthur Willert Sums Up U. S. A. as a Medley of Contradictions," Anglo-American News, pp. 252-254., 1936 June (Box 16, Folder 96)
    - "Roosevelt vor der Wahl," Europäische Revue, pp. 540-549., 1936 July (Box 16, Folder 97)
    - "Europe in 1936," Proceedings of the Institute of Public Affairs, pp. 52-65., 1936 July (Box 16, Folder 98)
    - "The American Scene," reprinted from International Affairs, pp. 543-560., 1936 July-August (Box 16, Folder 99)
    - "The King's Messengers," Strand Magazine, pp. 370- 378., 1936 August (Box 16, Folder 100)
    - "The Future of the League," review of The League of Nations and the Rule of Law, by Alfred Zimmern, Quarterly Review., autumn 1936 (Box 16, Folder 101)
    - "Europe Waits on Britain," The Fortnightly, pp. 257-267., 1936 September (Box 16, Folder 102)
    - "International Affairs," typescript of three-part article., 1936 September 17 (Box 16, Folder 103)
    - "America Elects…," Nash's, pp. 80-83., 1936 October 30 (Box 16, Folder 104)
    - "Roosevelt Zwischen Tradition and Reform," Europäische Revue, pp. 939-950., 1937 (Box 16, Folder 105)
    - "The Atlantic: Bond or Barrier?," reprinted from The Spectator, pp. 3-29., 1937 (Box 16, Folder 106)
    - "England's Duty," The Atlantic Monthly, pp. 96-104., 1937 January (Box 16, Folder 107)
    - "The Empire in the World", 1937 March (Box 16, Folder 108)
    - "The Press and Diplomacy," The Barnwell Bulletin, pp. 5-20., 1937 May (Box 16, Folder 109)
    - Untitled article for The Spectator, 1937 May (Box 16, Folder 110)
    - "British News Abroad," reprinted from The Round Table, pp. 533-546., 1937 June (Box 16, Folder 111)
    - "England und das Empire," Europäische Revue, pp. 423-432., 1937 June (Box 16, Folder 112)
    - Untitled article on France for The Spectator, 1937 July 25 (Box 16, Folder 113)
    - "Peace Through Freer Trade," The Listener, pp. 651-652, 687., 1937 September (Box 16, Folder 114)
    - "Retreat from Geneva," The Fortnightly, pp. 257-267., 1937 September (Box 16, Folder 115)
    - "The Distempers of Europe," The Atlantic Monthly, pp. 374-381., 1937 September (Box 16, Folder 116)
    - Untitled article for The New Commonwealth, 1937 September 25 (Box 16, Folder 117)
    - "Ambassadors to Britain," Strand Magazine, pp. 44-52., 1937 November (Box 16, Folder 118)
    - "Imperial Preference and American Trade," The Spectator, pp. 941-942., 1937 November 26 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - "Stopping the Drift to War," The New Commonwealth, pp. 64-65., 1938 January (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - "Le pacte franco-soviétique et la Grande-Bretagne," L'Esprit International, pp. 185-198., 1938 April (Box 16, Folder 121)
    - "The Crisis," The Contemporary Review, pp. 385-392., 1938 October (Box 17, Folder 122)
    - "Munich and the Issues for Democracy," The New Commonwealth Quarterly, pp. 292-295., 1938 December (Box 17, Folder 123)
    - "National Advertisement," The Fortnightly, pp. 1-7., 1939 January (Box 17, Folder 124)
    - "European Background," Journal of the Royal United Service Institution, pp. 153-163., 1939 February (Box 17, Folder 125)
    - "British News Controls," Foreign Affairs, pp. 712-722., 1939 July (Box 17, Folder 126)
    - "America: 1917 and 1941," Picture Post, pp. 9-15., 1941 May 31 (Box 17, Folder 127)
    - Letter to the Editor, The (London) Times, undated (Box 17, Folder 128)
    - "Great Britain and Europe," Hungarian Quarterly, pp. 586-592. (Box 17, Folder 129)
    - "The Hull Plan" (typed draft), undated (Box 17, Folder 130)
    - Typed draft of obituary of Sir Victor Wellesley, undated (Box 17, Folder 131)
    - "Panama Canal," scheme for a series of articles., undated (Box 17, Folder 132)
    - Untitled article, undated (Box 17, Folder 133)
    - Essays, undated (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - "Book Lecturing" (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - "Motoring" (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - "Recipe for Happiness after 50" (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - "Wind" (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - "The Gentleness of the English Climate" (Box 17, Folder 134)
  - Lectures
    - Resumé and itineraries from lecture tours, 1936, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - Syllabus of lecture course at Oxford, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - "The American Scene," address given at Chatham House 1936 May 12, reprinted in International Affairs, 1936 Jul-Aug. (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - "The Press and Diplomacy," Barnwell Foundation Address, 1937 Mar 15, Central High School, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, reprinted in The Barnwell Bulletin, 1937 May. (Box 17, Folder 138)
    - Untitled lecture on Russia, 1938 February 5 (Box 17, Folder 139)
  - Books and Reviews
    - Reviews of (Box 18, Folder 140)
      - Aspects of British Foreign Policy, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 140)
      - What Next in Europe?, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 140)
      - The Frontiers of England, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 140)
    - Reviews of (Box 18, Folder 141)
      - The Empire in the World, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 141)
      - The Atlantic: Bond or Barrier?, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 141)
    - Reviews of (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - The Road to Safety, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - Washington and Other Memories, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 142)
    - [Geoffrey Dawson and Our Times] Manuscript of From Thames to Potomac, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 143)
    - From Thames to Potomac, Miscellaneous Drafts
      - Chapters 1-2 (Box 18, Folder 144)
      - Chapters 3-4 (Box 18, Folder 145)
      - Chapters 5-6 (Box 18, Folder 146)
      - Chapters 7-8 (Box 18, Folder 147)
      - Chapters 9-10 (Box 18, Folder 148)
      - Chapters 11-12 (Box 18, Folder 149)
      - Chapters 13-14 (Box 19, Folder 150)
      - Chapters 15-16 (Box 19, Folder 151)
      - Chapters 17-19 (Box 19, Folder 152)
      - Chapters 20-21 (Box 19, Folder 153)
      - Chapters 22-23 (Box 19, Folder 154)
    - Washington and Other Memories (originally titled Decline Through Victory )
      - Chapters 1-5 (Box 19, Folder 155)
      - Chapters 6-10 (Box 19, Folder 156)
      - Chapters 11-15 (Box 19, Folder 157)
      - Chapters 16-20 (Box 19, Folder 158)
      - Chapters 21-24 (Box 19, Folder 159)
      - Manuscript rewrite of Chapters 7, 15, 17, 18, 21 (Box 20, Folder 160)
      - Manuscript rewrite of Chapters 22, 23, 24 (Box 20, Folder 161)
      - notes (miscellaneous) (Box 20, Folder 162)
    - notes for book, 1965 January 20 (Box 20, Folder 163)
    - notebook: "Index" of proposed chapters, undated (Box 20, Folder 164)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 4?] (Box 20, Folder 165)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 5] (Box 20, Folder 166)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 6] (Box 20, Folder 167)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 7] (Box 21, Folder 168)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 8] (Box 21, Folder 169)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 9] (Box 21, Folder 170)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 10] (Box 21, Folder 171)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 10] (Box 21, Folder 172)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 11] (Box 21, Folder 173)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 14] (Box 21, Folder 174)